<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creality Ender 3 S1 | Andreas Zwanenburg Portfolio</title>
    <link>/tag/creality-ender-3-s1/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/creality-ender-3-s1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Creality Ender 3 S1</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Creality Ender 3 S1</title>
      <link>/tag/creality-ender-3-s1/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D printing</title>
      <link>/project/3d-printing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/3d-printing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the start of my HBO Mechatronics studies, my interest in 3D printing has grown, leading to significant learning experiences. Over the past 7 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve delved into various aspects, such as optimizing material-print settings and mastering 3D design in Solidworks for lightweight, strong, and durable prints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my HBO study projects, I designed numerous parts and small-scale machines in Solidworks, translating these designs into 3D-printed realities. During my first internship, I revived an old and mallfunctioning Ultimaker Original, one of the pioneers in consumer 3D printers, from 2011. Over time, I enhanced its capabilities by modifying electronics, creating a new hotend and adding a heated bed. The printer is shown in the image at the top of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After five years, I decided to upgrade to the Creality Ender 3 S1 for a quieter and more precise printing experience. This printer automates many calibrations and fine-tuning processes, minimizing the need for manual adjustments and ensuring smoother prints, especially with its acceleration sensor for automatic tuning and reduced vibrations at high speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my 3D printing journey, printing on avarage roughly two parts per week, I have actively engaged in designing, printing, and refining. This hands-on approach has provided valuable insights into material properties and additive manufacturing processes. I now have a comprehensive understanding of selecting materials based on factors like durability, sun exposure, chemical requirements, and brittleness. Additionally, for the part design, the layer-by-layer printing process has taught me to consider factors such as layer orientation for strength, the necessity of support structures, and the precision required for achieving strength, lightweightness, and speed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
