<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Factory | Andreas Zwanenburg Portfolio</title>
    <link>/tag/factory/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/factory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Factory</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Factory</title>
      <link>/tag/factory/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industrial robot cell</title>
      <link>/project/industrial-robot-cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/industrial-robot-cell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my HBO Mechatronics graduation internship, I contributed to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vanweeswaalwijk.nl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Machinefabriek Van Wees Waalwijk&lt;/a&gt;, a company specializing in industrial automations. In this internship, I design a stacking carrousel system to feed trays of strawberries into a process utilizing a 6-axis robotic arm in an industrial bakery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the internship, I continued my collaboration with the company during the summer break and for four additional months in the subsequent year. In this extended period, I served as an engineer, actively involved in machine designs and assemblies. Additionally, I visited the company&amp;rsquo;s clients, where I analysd existing machine processes. My role included conducting objective assessments of machine performance, identifying bottlenecks, and proposing optimization strategies for both the machine design and the customer&amp;rsquo;s processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;internship&#34;&gt;Internship&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the internship project, I was tasked with designing a carousel system for trays of strawberries to seamlessly integrate into an existing robot cell featuring a UR10 6-axis robot within an industrial bakery. The goal was to facilitate the efficient picking of strawberries by the robot arm from a stack of trays inserted by an employee.
Given the industrial food environment, the design was subject to strict cleaning requirements. Every detail, including edges, corners, holes, and other openings, was carefully designed to optimize the cleaning process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the PLC in the system needed to seamlessly interface with the PLC of the robot arm. Consequently, a PLC program with this communication capability was designed and programmed for this task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rendering of the carrousel&amp;rsquo;s Solidworks design is shown in the image below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;aardbeien_carrousel.png&#34; alt=&#34;Caption&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;machine-design-assembly-and-optimalisation&#34;&gt;Machine design, assembly and optimalisation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the internship, Van Wees offered me a summer side job, and the following year, I continued my involvement with the company for an additional four months after completing my study program in the spring. During this period, I engaged in various projects, doing various tasks including robot programming, optimization, field analysis, mechanical assembly, and electrical assembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For programming robots within multi-station robot cells, featuring UR10 collaborative and Epson Scara LS6 robots, I focused on enhancing efficiency. This involved analyzing task execution orders, optimizing robot motions, and implementing additional logic to make the systems more adaptive to dynamic situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For deployed production machines operating in the field for several years, I did an objective alalysis and adviced both Van Wees and the customer. My approach involved studying the product and the customer&amp;rsquo;s process, logging machine production data, and conducting a thorough analysis of the results how downtime can be decreased and production optimised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contributing to the production of Van Wees machines, I found great satisfaction in both mechanical and electrical assembly tasks. In mechanical assembly, I followed design schematics to assemble parts, while in electrical assembly, I installed numerous sensors on robot cells. This included adjusting cable ducts to the correct size, wiring sensors to can-bus hubs, and connecting can-bus hubs to the PLC. I particularly enjoyed installing and wiring the electronic components at the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
